# ADEKA EMMANUELLA ONYOWO

HSE 35, Erelu Ayisat Street, Oniru Resettlement Housing Scheme , VI, Lagos, Nigeria

Phone: +234-906-028-9026 adekaeatwork@gmail.com

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated and experienced web developer with 2+ years of experience specializing in websites and web applications. Extensive background in full stack development lifecycle including design, coding, and debugging of web applications. Have also done numerous projects involving front or back end development singly.

# **EDUCATION**

#### VERITAS UNIVERSITY ABUJA

B.Sc Industrial Chemistry (2015 - 2019)

# **AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS**

Full Stack Developer (Certificate of Achievement)
Coding Towers Ltd
2020

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Junior Web Developer

Coding Towers Limited | 2019 - present

- Designed and developed web sites with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to increase target audience.
- Built landing pages with easy and simple navigation to improve user flow.
- Developed web apps with modern Python framework (Django).
- Coached tech enthusiasts basic frontend development.
- Created responsive websites with SCSS that allowed cross-platform accessibility on any device ranging from mobile phone to desktop.

#### Industrial Chemist Intern

OVH Energy | March 2018 - August 2018

- Performed testing using industry standard methods.
- · Analysis of raw materials and final products samples.
- Performed Quality Assurance and Quality Control tests on samples before and after packaging of the products and also lab procedures.
- Maintained accurate logbooks and required documentation.

# **PROJECTS**

# Beachy E-commerce App

Duration: 2months

Technology used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Django.

- Created a user-friendly interface.
- Made web app responsive to accommodate numerous devices including mobile phones.
- Added numerous payment options for the customers to choose from.
- Added a blog
- · Developed product inventory.
- Developed an admin panel to improve order management, inventory management, price management, payment tracking, & shipping and delivery management.

# Fotocafe Website (Photography)

Duration: 3weeks

Technology used: HTML, CSS, Django.

- Built a landing page with simple navigation
- · Used different themes for different galleries to improve navigation.
- Made web app responsive to accommodate numerous devices including mobile phones.

# Web App for Lingfield Pharmacy (For ordering prescriptions)

Duration: 6months

Technology used: HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, Django.

- · Rebuilt entire web application with Django website.
- Developed an admin panel to improve order management, inventory management, price management, payment tracking, & shipping and delivery management.
- Added a smart search feature for advanced search, sorting, & filtering option to allow users quickly search for products.
- · Responsive to fit different devices mobile to desktop.

# **SKILLS**

GENERAL: MS Office, Critical Thinking, Communication, Problem-Solving, Collaboration

TECHNICAL: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Django, Git, Ul Design, Graphic Design, Adobe Creative

Suite, Figma, Canva

PRODUCTIVITY: Notion, Trello